<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Peter Mackay</title><link>https://petmac.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Peter Mackay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 23:04:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://petmac.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Object-oriented Programming (OOP)</title><link>https://petmac.dev/posts/oop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 16:58:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://petmac.dev/posts/oop/</guid><description>What is OOP? First, read Wikipedia.
Characteristics of OOP Division of the problem into Objects which implement Classes The programmer is able to model the problem space in terms of objects that talk to each other via messages (method calls.)
I believe this to be a poor approach to most data transformation problems.
Accidental complexity By writing this “architecture” code that does not directly address the data transformation problems at hand, we have burdened ourselves with accidental complexity and latent problems that will at some point prevent us from solving the actual problems we have.</description></item><item><title>What is Programming?</title><link>https://petmac.dev/posts/what-is-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 16:22:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://petmac.dev/posts/what-is-programming/</guid><description>Introduction This page borrows heavily from Mike Acton.
Transformation of data Writing code is a means to solving a problem, and primarily the problem is that some data (input) needs to be transformed into something else (output).
Examples of inputs:
Button taps Incoming HTTP responses Events coming from the OS Events coming from 3rd party SDKs Examples of outputs:
The view hierarchy Audio HTTP requests Requests sent to 3rd party SDKs Frequently the output is not only dependent on any particular input, but on some stored state that is maintained as the app runs.</description></item></channel></rss>